<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

    <channel>
        <title>Knowledgedoc Technical Writing Blog</title>
        <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/</link>
        <description>
            The Knowledgedoc blog features discussions of the technical writing profession, knowledge management
            techniques and tips for writing, editing, formatting and using documentation based software applications.
        </description>
        <item>
            <title>Planning creatively for documentation projects</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/planning-creatively.html</link>
            <description>
                Thinking creatively is an essential skill for technical writers. Over three articles I will explore some
                of the ways creativity can be employed during a documentation project. This week is all about the planning
                stage and several ways creativity can help you manage a documentation project.
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Converting Word documents to online outputs</title>
            <link>
                http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/converting-word-to-online.html
            </link>
            <description>
                We humans forget how old we really are: we contain 14.3 billion year old hydrogen molecules and 3.6 billion year old life-giving molecules such as DNA and its precursors. It’s little wonder that we’re very good at breathing but not so good at driving (since 1888) or using Microsoft Word (since 1983). Project sponsors usually over-estimate the ability of their subject matter experts to use Word to create online content for their end-user audience. I look at some of the steps to reformat and prepare a Word document to import into our authoring tool; enabling us to create a variety of outputs, including online help.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How to write web content for search engines</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/writing-for-search-engines.html</link>
            <description>
                Rachel discusses the best way to write web content that will be noticed by search engines.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Five reasons to use Word styles</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/use-word-styles.html</link>
            <description>
                Sue shares her top five reasons to make the time to learn how to use Word styles.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Project management for writers</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/project-management-for-writers.html</link>
            <description>
                This week features a Southern Communicator article by Penelope Goward and Sue Woolley discussing their
                techniques for managing writing projects. Penelope and Sue also run courses in project management for writers.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Word tips - How to set up numbered headings</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/numbered-headings.html</link>
            <description>
                Numbered headings can be very useful for organising your document into sections. This article will cover
                using Word’s predefined numbered headings and setting up your own numbered heading scheme.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Capturing content for mobile devices</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/capturing-content.html</link>
            <description>
                I’m a dinosaur when it comes to mobile devices. What did I do when faced with capturing content for a
                mobile app from an iPhone? Call in one of the children to help of course.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Creative traps in technical communication</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/creative-traps.html</link>
            <description>
                Creativity is an essential skill for technical communicators, but it must be carefully managed
                to ensure the quality of the content is not being compromised. This article looks at three of the most
                common errors made by writers making the switch from creative to technical writing.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Software documentation - How much or how little?</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/software-documentation.html</link>
            <description>A discussion of the necessity of software documentation in current society.</description>
        </item>

    </channel>

</rss>