<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <channel>
        <title>Knowledgedoc Technical Writing Blog</title>
        <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            The Knowledgedoc blog features discussions of the technical writing profession, knowledge management
            techniques and tips for writing, editing, formatting and using documentation based software applications.
        </description>
        <item>
            <title>Alignment tab</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/alignment-tab.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/alignment-tab.html</guid>
            <description>
                From Word 2007 onwards a special type of tab stop called an alignment tab has been introduced. You
                can use the alignment tab in headers and footers to automatically readjust the position of the text
                depending on the margins or page orientation.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Introductions to sections</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-sections.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-sections.html</guid>
            <description>
                Microsoft Word documents can be separated into sections. Sections are important for many reasons,
                you can organise your document into chapters with sections and have pages change design and layout
                throughout your document.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Localising content using single sourcing</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/localising-with-single-sourcing.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/localising-with-single-sourcing.html</guid>
            <description>
                Because Australia is part of the Asia-Pacific region, some organisations need to produce foreign-language
                versions of their content. The cost and turnaround time of translating and localising content can be
                significantly reduced by using single sourcing techniques and tools.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Getting to know Adobe Illustrator</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-adobe-illustrator.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-adobe-illustrator.html</guid>
            <description>
                Adobe Creative Cloud is an awesome suite of applications for anyone looking to add additional polish
                to documentation. One of the most useful applications in the suite is Adobe Illustrator. This article introduces the
                main functions of Adobe Illustrator.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ten things I bet you didn't know a technical writer could do</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/10-things-technical-writers-do.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/10-things-technical-writers-do.html</guid>
            <description>
                Technical writers don’t just write. And we don’t just write technical information. Here are 10 things that
                technical writers can do that you might not be aware of.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Coordinating caption and page numbers with headings</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/numbered-captions-and-pages.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/numbered-captions-and-pages.html</guid>
            <description>
                If you’ve set up numbered headings in your Microsoft Word document you
                might be wondering how to coordinate all the other numbers in your document with your headings. This
                article will discuss ways to add chapter numbers to page numbers and caption numbers, in the format of 1-1,
                1-2 for chapter 1 and 2-1, 2-2 for chapter 2. Typically you use the Heading 1 style to signify a new chapter.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Creating single sourcing topics</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/creating-single-sourcing-topics.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/creating-single-sourcing-topics.html</guid>
            <description>
                In this article I delve into how we isolate common content into a topic and reuse it many times in other topics.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Managing your creative bank</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/creative-bank.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/creative-bank.html</guid>
            <description>
                The technical writer is the communication industry’s version of a Swiss-army knife. For any given project
                a technical writer is required to draw upon skills covering writing, graphic design, programming, and
                project management. Achieving this goal means effectively managing and updating your “creative bank” of skills.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Documentation, printed or online?</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/online-or-printed.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/online-or-printed.html</guid>
            <description>
                This article discusses whether there is any place for printed documentation in 2015.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Creating an RSS feed</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/making-an-rss-feed.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/making-an-rss-feed.html</guid>
            <description>
                Rich Site Summaries, known as RSS feeds, are a great way to publish frequently updated information
                such as news or blog articles. This article will discuss how to create and maintain an RSS feed on your website.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Introduction to single sourcing</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-single-sourcing.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-single-sourcing.html</guid>
            <description>
                Writing content once, then reusing it provides many benefits. You can organise your content better,
                reduce its overall cost and publish it for viewing on the favourite devices of your users.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 12:50:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Publishing creatively in technical writing</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/publishing-creatively.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/publishing-creatively.html</guid>
            <description>
                Being creative during the publishing phase is challenging. Unlike the planning and writing phases, which
                have rich creative possibilities, the publishing phase is characterised by rigid output formats and methodical tasks.
                In this article I will discuss employing creativity in the publishing phase.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 16:50:00 +1000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Changing the display order of styles in the Quick Styles gallery</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/changing-word-styles-order.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/changing-word-styles-order.html</guid>
            <description>
                Once you have set up your Quick Styles gallery with the styles you use most frequently,
                you should change the order so that your most frequently-used styles are at the beginning of the
                list. This will speed up the style selection process.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 11:09:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Introduction to RSS feeds</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-rss.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/introduction-to-rss.html</guid>
            <description>
                For years I’ve seen the acronym RSS around, or the bright orange RSS symbol
                but it wasn’t until I started managing the Knowledgedoc blog that I actually investigated what these
                things were.  It turns out that an RSS feed is a really great tool for following a blog. In this
                article I’ll introduce you to RSS feeds and how to follow all your favourite organisations.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Writing creatively for documentation projects</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/writing-creatively.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/writing-creatively.html</guid>
            <description>
                Technical documentation must always be accurate and easy-to-understand. This means using unambiguous
                terms, avoiding long sentences, and enabling users to easily find information. This can sound a bit
                dry, but crafting good documentation requires a creative mindset during each project phase.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Preparing online content for Word and PDF outputs</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/preparing-online-content.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/preparing-online-content.html</guid>
            <description>
                For over a dozen years we’ve been delivering online help and printable information for the many based on the expertise of the few.
                To produce printable information, we publish from our authoring tool to Microsoft Word and save from there to a PDF.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Making the Word Quick Styles gallery useful</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/word-quick-styles.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/word-quick-styles.html</guid>
            <description>
                Sue discusses getting the most out of Microsoft Word's Quick Styles panel, customising the styles appearing on the
                panel to best suit your needs.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning creatively for documentation projects</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/planning-creatively.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/planning-creatively.html</guid>
            <description>
                Thinking creatively is an essential skill for technical writers. Over three articles I will explore some
                of the ways creativity can be employed during a documentation project. This week is all about the planning
                stage and several ways creativity can help you manage a documentation project.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Converting Word documents to online outputs</title>
            <link>
                http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/converting-word-to-online.html
            </link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/converting-word-to-online.html</guid>
            <description>
                We humans forget how old we really are: we contain 14.3 billion year old hydrogen molecules and 3.6 billion year old life-giving molecules such as DNA and its precursors. It’s little wonder that we’re very good at breathing but not so good at driving (since 1888) or using Microsoft Word (since 1983). Project sponsors usually over-estimate the ability of their subject matter experts to use Word to create online content for their end-user audience. I look at some of the steps to reformat and prepare a Word document to import into our authoring tool; enabling us to create a variety of outputs, including online help.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How to write web content for search engines</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/writing-for-search-engines.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/writing-for-search-engines.html</guid>
            <description>
                Rachel discusses the best way to write web content that will be noticed by search engines.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Five reasons to use Word styles</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/use-word-styles.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/use-word-styles.html</guid>
            <description>
                Sue shares her top five reasons to make the time to learn how to use Word styles.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Project management for writers</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/project-management-for-writers.pdf</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/project-management-for-writers.pdf</guid>
            <description>
                This week features a Southern Communicator article by Penelope Goward and Sue Woolley discussing their
                techniques for managing writing projects. Penelope and Sue also run courses in project management for writers.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Word tips - How to set up numbered headings</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/numbered-headings.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/numbered-headings.html</guid>
            <description>
                Numbered headings can be very useful for organising your document into sections. This article will cover
                using Word’s predefined numbered headings and setting up your own numbered heading scheme.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Capturing content for mobile devices</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/capturing-content.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/capturing-content.html</guid>
            <description>
                I’m a dinosaur when it comes to mobile devices. What did I do when faced with capturing content for a
                mobile app from an iPhone? Call in one of the children to help of course.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Creative traps in technical communication</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/creative-traps.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/creative-traps.html</guid>
            <description>
                Creativity is an essential skill for technical communicators, but it must be carefully managed
                to ensure the quality of the content is not being compromised. This article looks at three of the most
                common errors made by writers making the switch from creative to technical writing.
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Software documentation - How much or how little?</title>
            <link>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/software-documentation.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.knowledgedoc.com.au/blog/articles/software-documentation.html</guid>
            <description>A discussion of the necessity of software documentation in current society.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 13:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        </item>

    </channel>

</rss>